Guide to the Paul Buhle Papers TAM.171
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Paul Buhle Papers
1884-2000
1964-1992
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Buhle, Paul, 1944-
TAM.171
6.25 Linear Feet in 15 manuscript boxes
Paul Buhle is a scholar of radicalism in the United States and the Caribbean, with particular emphasis on its cultural manifestations, and of the Immigrant Left. This collection documents his political and intellectual life, including his interest and involvement in the antiwar movement, the activism of the New Left, the "radical history" movement of the 1970s, and efforts to create a "radical humor movement." Materials include correspondence, published and unpublished writings, Buhle's collection of satirical and other humor publications, and research files on radical immigrant communities and Afro-Trinidadian historian and social theorist CLR James.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Materials were donated by Paul Buhle in circa 1986. The accession number associated with this gift is 1995.010.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into four series, two of which have been further arranged in subseries. The series and subseries arrangement of the materials is as follows:
Missing Title
Series 1, Correspondence, 1965-1993
Series 2, Research Files, 1911-1992
Subseries 1, Immigrant Left Files, 1911-1989
Subseries 2, CLR James Files, 1939-1992
Series 3, Graphic Materials, 1884-2000
Series 4, Writings, 1964-1992
Subseries 1, Unpublished Writings, 1964-1992
Subseries 2, Published Writings, 1966-1991
Biographical Note
Paul Buhle (1944- ) is a scholar of radicalism in the United States and the Caribbean, with particular emphasis on its cultural manifestations, and of the Immigrant Left. Buhle was born in Urbana, Illinois, attended the University of Illinois (B.A., 1966), the University of Connecticut (M.A., 1967), and the University of Wisconsin - Madison (Ph.D., 1975). Buhle taught at the Cambridge-Godard School (1971–1973), the Rhode Island School of Design, and Brown University (1995-), where he is currently Faculty Emeritus.
Buhle was an active participant in the New Left of the 1960s and 1970s. He was a spokesperson for the University of Illinois' chapter of Students for a Democratic Society's (SDS) antiwar and civil rights activities. Buhle was the founding editor, along with Mary Jo Buhle, of the journal Radical America (1967–1999), which began as an unofficial organ of SDS and focused on issues such as civil rights, women's liberation, working class radicalism, and the anti-war movement. During the 1970s the journal began to shift its focus toward the issues and priorities of the New Left, as opposed to the more traditional values of the "Old Left." Buhle also founded Cultural Correspondence (1977–1983), a popular culture studies journal. For a brief period Buhle was a member of the Socialist Labor Party. In 2006 and 2007, he became one of the founding figures of the new Students for a Democratic Society, and more recently a leader of the Movement for a Democratic Society.
Buhle is the author or editor of numerous books, including Students for a Democratic Society: A Graphic History (2008); Wobblies! A Graphic History of Industrial Workers of the World (2005); Radical Hollywood: The Untold Story Behind America's Favorite Movies (2002); Images of American Radicalism (1998); The Immigrant Left in the United States (1996); Encyclopedia of the American Left (1990); Marxism in the United States: Remapping the History of the American Left (1987); C.L.R. James, His Life and Work (1986); and Labor's Joke Book (1985). Buhle was also one of the organizers of and chief contributors to the Oral History of the American Left (1984-), a project of the Tamiment Library at NYU. He co-founded the Rhode Island Labor History Society and produced Vanishing Road Island and Underground Rhode Island.
Scope and Content Note
This collection documents the political and intellectual life of Paul Buhle, including his interest and involvement in the antiwar movement, the activism of the New Left, the "radical history" movement of the 1970s, and efforts to create a "radical humor movement." Materials in this collection also document Buhle's research on radical immigrant communities, his research on Afro-Trinidadian historian and social theorist CLR James, and the founding and activities of his journals, Radical America and Cultural Correspondence. The collection also contains Buhle's writings, including journalism for many leftist publications, numerous book reviews, unrealized essay drafts, and undergraduate and graduate school papers.
Radicals -- United States.; Hungarian Americans.; Czech Americans.; Caricatures and cartoons.; Caricatures and cartoons -- United States.; Comic books.; Correspondence.; Radicalism -- United States.; Political cartoons.; Socialism -- United States.; New Left -- United States.; Manuscripts; Communism -- United States.; Wit and humor, American.; Slavic Americans.; Political satire, American.; Political cartoons -- United States.; James, C. L. R. (Cyril Lionel Robert), 1901-1989; Buhle, Paul, 1944-; Buhle, Paul, 1944-
- Series I, Correspondence, 1965-1993, 1966-1993
  Arrangement
  Series is arranged chronologically.
  Scope and Content Note
  This series consists of incoming and outgoing correspondence between Paul Buhle and numerous individuals on subjects such as the historiography of labor movements, the emergence of popular culture criticism, the role of humor in radical political movements, the activities of Buhle's journals, Radical America and Cultural Correspondence, and the possible ways to refigure Marxism and socialism in the late 20th-century. Frequent correspondents include Franklin Rosemont, founder of the Chicago Surrealist Group; political writer and theorist Paul Berman; Trotskyist political theorist Alan Woods; labor historian David Montgomery; Thomas H. Fiehrer, Southern historian and editor of Plantation Society in the Americas; anarchist poet and historian Dan Georgakas; Jewish editor and humorist Larry Bush; and anarchist cartoonist Jay Kinney. Other correspondents include actors Edward Asner and Eddy Albert; writers and theorists Frederic Jameson, Stuart Hall, Malcom Cowley, CLR James, Marge Piercy, Irving Howe, Ring Lardner, Jr., Edward Said, Alexander Saxton, and David Platt; labor, social, and cultural historians Herbert Gutman, Eric Foner, William Appleman Williams, David Brody, Phillip Foner, Herbert Aptheker, George Lipsitz; artists Art Spiegelman, R. Crumb, Bill Griffith, Maurice Kish; leftist political activists H.L. Mitchell, Gil Green, Will Weinstone, Joseph Starobin, and Paul Novick; editors of publications like the Village Voice, Nation, Seven Days, Morgn Freiheit, and Jewish Forward; as well as numerous poets, labor movement veterans, leftwing political activists, and radical scholars.
  - 1965-1972, 1966-1972 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1973 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Jan 1974-Nov 1974 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Dec 1974 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Jan 1975-Mar 1975 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Apr 1975-Jun 1975 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Jul 1975-Sep 1975 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Oct 1975-Nov 1975, Oct-Nov 1975 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Dec 1975 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Jan 1976-Feb 1976 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Mar 1976-Jun 1976 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Jul 1976-Nov 1976 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Dec 1976 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Jan 1977-May 1977 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Jun 1977-Dec 1977 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Jan 1978-Aug 1978 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Sep 1978-Dec 1978 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 1979 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Jan 1980-Jun 1980 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Jul 1980-Dec 1980 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Jan 1981-Jun 1981 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Jul 1981-Nov 1981 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Dec 1981 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Jan 1982-Aug 1982 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Sep 1982-Dec 1982 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Jan 1983-Jul 1983 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Aug 1983-Dec 1983 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - 1984 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Jan 1985-Aug 1985 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Sep 1985-Dec 1985 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Jan 1986-Jun 1986 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Jul 1986-Nov 1986 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Dec 1986 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Jan 1987-Jul 1987 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Oct 1987-Dec 1987 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - 1988 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - 1989 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - 1990 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - 1991 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - 1992 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - 1993 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Series II, Research Files, 1911-1992
  Series is arranged into two subseries, both of which are arranged alphabetically.
  - Subseries I, Immigrant Left Files, 1911-1989
    Materials in this subseries consist of Buhle's research concerning immigrant radicalism in the 19th-century, with specific focus on Hungarian, Polish, Russian, Slovenian, and Ukrainian immigrant communities.
    Subseries is arranged alphabetically.
    - Czechoslovakia: "Czechs in Cleveland: A Study in Ethnic Socialism, 1902-1938" by Gregory M. Stone, Nov 21, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Czechoslovakia: "Free Thought and Socialism in the Czech Community in Chicago, 1875-1887" by Richard Schneirov, circa 1984 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Czechoslovakia: "A Study of Radicalism in the Bohemian-American Community" by Joseph Chada, circa 1954 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Finland: Interviews, 1976-1982 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Finland: Secondary Sources, 1976-1980 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - France: "Socialism in America: The French-speaking Coal Miners" by Ronald Creagh", circa 1988 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Greece: General, circa 1985 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Greece: "The Greeks in America" by Dan Georgakas, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Hungary: General, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Hungary: Newspapers: Bermunkás, 1924-1931 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Hungary: Newspapers: Magyar Jova, circa 1941 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Hungary: Newspapers: Új Elöre, 1922 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Hungary: Newspapers: Új Elöre, 1924-1926 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Hungary: Newspapers: Új Elöre, 1928-1936 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Hungary: Newspapers: Others, 1911-1931 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Hungary: Secondary Sources, 1977-1985 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Lithuania: "US Left and Labor Movements: The Role of the Lithuanians" by Rudolph Baranik, undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Poland: General, undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Poland: Dziennek Lodwy (People's Daily) articles, 1907 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Poland: Notecards, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Poland: "Packingtown Polonia: The Polish Worker and the Development of Community in Chicago's Stock Yard District" by Dominic A. Pacyga, Oct 10, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Poland: "Polish-American Socialism, 1880-1950" by Mary Eleanor Cygan (1 of 2 folders), 1989 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Poland: "Polish-American Socialism, 1880-1950" by Mary Eleanor Cygan (2 of 2 folders), 1989 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Poland: World War I, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Russia: General (1 of 2 folders), undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Russia: General (2 of 2 folders), undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Russia: Notes by Maria Woroby (1 of 2 folders), undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Russia: Notes by Maria Woroby (2 of 2 folders), undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Slovenia: "In Unity is Strength: A History of the Slovene National Benefit Society, 1904-1985" by Joseph Stipanovich (1 of 2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Slovenia: "In Unity is Strength: A History of the Slovene National Benefit Society, 1904-1985" by Joseph Stipanovich (2 of 2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Ukraine: General (1 of 2 folders), undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Ukraine: General (2 of 2 folders), undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Ukraine: Newspapers, 1914-1922 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Subseries II, CLR James Files, 1939-1992
    Materials in this subseries include correspondence, newspaper articles, unpublished writings, and published writings concerning Buhle's relationship with and research on the Afro-Trinidadian historian and social theorist CLR James. The subseries contains correspondence between Buhle, James, James' ex-wife Constance Webb, Guyanese writer Wilson Harris, poet E. Ethelbert Miller, historian Noel Ignatiev, historian George Rawick, and other individuals involved in James' personal and professional life. The subseries also includes materials concerning Buhle's biography of James, including notes, preliminary drafts, and reviews. Also included are essays, obituaries of James, correspondence concerning the formation of the CLR James Society, and a chapter of James autobiography, My Life with Women.
    - Correspondence: CLR James and Constance Webb Pearlstien: General, Sep 1939-Sep 1948 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence: CLR James and Constance Webb Pearlstien: General, Nov 1948-Jul 1984 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence: CLR James and Constance Webb Pearlstien: "Autobiography of a Man By Himself" (1 of 2 folders), 1944 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence: CLR James and Constance Webb Pearlstien: "Autobiography of a Man By Himself" (2 of 2 folders), 1944 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence: CLR James and Paul Buhle, 1970-1983 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence: Paul Buhle and others about CLR James (1 of 2 folders), 1972-1992 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence: Paul Buhle and others about CLR James (2 of 2 folders), 1975-1992 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Interviews, 1981-1986 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1981-1992 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Obituaries, 1989-1990 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Reviews of Paul Buhle's work on CLR James, Aug 1982-May 1991 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Unpublished CLR James writings (1 of 2 folders), undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Unpublished CLR James writings (2 of 2 folders), undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Unpublished writings on CLR James (not by Paul Buhle), 1969-1991 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - "The West Indian at Home and Abroad: My Experience with Women," by CLR James, circa 1970 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Writings and speeches by CLR James, 1962-1968, 1981; 1962-1968 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Writings and drafts on CLR James by Paul Buhle, May 1984 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Series III, Graphic Materials, 1884-2000
  Series is arranged alphabetically.
  Materials in this series document Buhle's research interest in graphic non-fiction materials as artistic medium, radical humor produced in the 1970s and 1980s, and his involvement in the effort to create a radical humor movement. Materials consist of numerous American and European satirical publications, including substantial materials from the surrealist humorists, Yiddish humorists, the Texas-based Church of the SubGenius, and the Italian New Left of the 1970s and early 1980s. The series also includes materials from Buhle's lectures and exhibits on radical humor, including the 1982 Radical Humor Show at New York University and the traveling Radical Humor Exhibit (1982-1985).
  Existence and Location of Originals Note
  Series contains a substantial amount of photocopied cartoons and other graphic materials from a variety of institutions. The location of original items is sometimes indicated on the document; however, the location of some original items is unknown.
  - Adventures of Henry Dubb, circa 1912 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Aero, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Aftershock, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - The Agribiz Game, circa 1979 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Air Pirates Funnies, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Ameringer, Oscar, Aug 1925-Apr 1939 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Ammunition, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Appeal to Treason, 1982-1983 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Art Not War, circa 1980 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - The Austin Iconoclast Magazine, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Babushkin's Digest, Jan 1985-May 1987 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Lee Baxandall and Naturalism, Jun 1989 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Edward Bellamy, 1938 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Berkeley cartoons, circa 1960 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Bermack, Richard, undated (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Billboards of the Future, circa 1980 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - A Bridge Too Far, undated (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Bulletin of the I.S. Gay Caucus, Jul 1971 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - The Capital Times, Jul 13, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Church of the Subgenius, 1971-1979 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Church of the Subgenius, 1980-1982 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Church of the Subgenius, 1983-1985 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Church of the Subgenius, undated (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Collectors' Network News, Sep 1977-Dec 1977 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Comical Funnies, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Communism cartoons, undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Communist Cartoons, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Crawford, J., undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Cronaca Souversiva, Jan 20, 1917 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Crumb, R., Mar 1981 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Corsaren, Nov 1978 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Cultural Correspondence, 1974-1978 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Cultural Correspondence, 1979-1980 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Cultural Correspondence, 1981-1985 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - "Curious George Goes to Shul!", undated (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Cynical Man, Apr 15, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - "Dance of Love" by Vaga Verdaqus, Feb 25, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - The Dawn, 1914-1919 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Demonstrations, 1934 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Der Arme Teufel, 1884-1888 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Diamond, Abby, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Did God Ordain the Holocaust?, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Diversión, circa 1975 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Earth First!, undated (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Economy cartoons, undated (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - The End of the World's Fair, Jan 1983-May 1984 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Estuary Press catalog, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Feminist cartoons, undated (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Finnish Americana, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - First Strike?, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Friends of Progress record and tape club, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Freeze and Scream, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Funny Couch, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Good Morning, 1919-1921 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Groucho Marxism, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Hawaiian graphics, 1909, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - "Health and Laughter", 1984 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - "History of the Left Set to Supremes' Songs", Dec 30, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees, AFL-CIO, Local 5 (Honolulu, Hawaii), 1994 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - House of Humor and Satire, Nov 1982-Feb 1984 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Howe, Irving and Michael Harrington, Jun 17, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - "Humor in Art" exhibit at Pyramid Gallery, Rochester, NY, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - If, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - Il Male, Apr 1978-Oct 1979 (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - Il Male, Nov 1979-Apr 1980 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Il Male, May 1980-Aug 1980 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Il Proletario, 1915-1921 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - "In Good Conscience: The Radical Tradition in 20th-Century American Illustration", 2000 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Inside Joke, May 1982-Jun 1982 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - International Dictionary of Obscenities, May 1984 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - International Humor Movement, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - An International Treasury of Leftwing Humor, 1945 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Jim's Letter, Apr 26, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Labor cartoons, 1873-1933, undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Labor's Joke Book by Paul Buhle, Feb 1985 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Laser Project, circa 1983 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Less Newspoems, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Lovecraft, H.P., Aug 1990 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Lyons, Lisa, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Mangan, Sherry, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - The Match!, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - May Day, 1936 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - The Mill Hunk Herald, 1983-1984 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Molot, May 15, 1921 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Moorish Science Monitor, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Mother Jones posters, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Mucus, 1984-1985 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Nadir, Moishe, circa 1961 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - The National Grange Order of the Patrons of Husbandry, undated (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - New York Pioneer, 1887, 1894 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Not Available Comics, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Perlman, Freddy, circa 1968 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Photographic prints (1 of 2 folders), undated (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Photographic prints (2 of 2 folders), undated (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Playboy, Jan 1983 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Pop-Iliev, Jordan, circa 1970-1980 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Post New York Post, Nov 1984 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Processed World, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - "Protect the Rights of the Unconceived" by Don Fitz, Mar 1983 (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - The Puma Blues, 1986-1987 (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - The Puma Blues, 1987-1989 (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - Radical America, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - Radical Humor, Oct 1982 (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - Radical Humor Art Show (1 of 2 folders), 1982 (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - Radical Humor Art Show (2 of 2 folders), 1982 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Radical humor festival, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Radical humor lecture and slide show, circa 1984 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - The Radical Rag, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Real Hep! Comics, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - The Realist, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - The Rebel Worker, Jun 1966 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Red Sky Blue Sky, Sep 1970 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Religion cartoons, undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Rhode Island Voice, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Rhubarb, 1982-1984 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - The Rip-Saw Mother Goose by Henry M. Tichenor, 1912 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Rius (Eduardo del Rio), circa 1976 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Rumbles!, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Search and Destroy, 1977-1979 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Shevchenko, Taras, Mar 1964 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Shmate, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Sinister Wisdom, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Socialism cartoons, 1901-1979 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - The Southern California Library for Social Studies and Research, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Space City!, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Square Pegs, undated (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Students for a Democratic Society, Aug 19, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Surrealist movement, 1969-1973 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Surrealist movement, 1979-1989 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Suvanto, K.A., undated (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Tacky World, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Talkin' Union: Music, Lore, and History, Dec 1985 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Tongue, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Twisted Image, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - The Tuber's Voice: The Couch Potato Newsletter, 1980-1984 (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - "Underground Comix" essay by Don Schenker, undated (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - "Urban Humor in Houston", undated (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - The Vanguardian, circa 1978 (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - "Voices of the Left, 1870-1960" exhibit catalog (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Wage Slave World News, Jan 1989 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Weirdo, 1982 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - "What's the Use in Laughing?" Country Life, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - John Greenleaf Whittier, 1888 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Win, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Winds of Change, Aug 1980-Sep 1981 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Wood, Wally, circa 1967 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Workers' Democracy, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - World War 3 Illustrated, 1984-1986 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Yiddish cartoons, 1913-1943 (Box 12, Folder 11)
- Series IV, Writings, 1964-1992
  Series is arranged into two subseries, both of which are arranged chronologically.
  - Unpublished Writings, 1964-1992